# **Christopher Scholl**

chris.o.scholl@gmail.com | 734-972-3959 | 250 Village Green Blvd Apt 205, Ann Arbor, 48105 https://codepen.io/coscholl/project/full/AkoVyv https://github.com/coscholl | https://coscholl.github.io

# JavaScript Developer I

Autodidact with nearly 3 years of work experience at an insurance tech startup where I created web app improvements to make navigation easier for users, as well as making data editing and rendering in the web browser more efficient. 3 years of JavaScript experience focusing on ECMAScript 2015 (ES6) standards and beyond, applying the functional programming paradigm to React applications and HTML documents.

# Experience -

#### Consultant and Web Developer, Gabriel Urist Jewelry

July - Sept 2020

Website consultant for internationally renown jeweler

Custom elements using HTML, SVG, and CSS

#### Front End Web Developer,

Data Analyst, Groundspeed Analytics, Inc, Ann Arbor, MI

Oct 2017 - Apr 2020

Web application development for fast growing insurance tech startup

- Functional JavaScript application development on a MongoDB + Express + Node + React stack
- Class-based JavaScript application development using a Meteor + React stack with Redux state management
- MaterialUI styling along with CSS (grid and flexbox proficiency)
- Code documentation using JSDoc3 standard
- Agile development with version control using Git and Docker on Linux (Ubuntu) OS
- Recognized for excellent communication

#### **Exhibit Assistant**

Michigan Medicine, Ann Arbor, MI

Dec 2014 - Oct 2017

Installation and de-installation of 8 art gallery spaces at University of Michigan Hospital

Art handling, installation, inventory, packing, and storage

Skills ——

**Productivity Tools** Jira, Trello, Zoom, Slack, Google Meet

Web Analytics Google Analytics, Segment.io

**Languages** English, Spanish

Other ABBYY Flexilayout Studio, ABBYY Finereader

## Education —

## **System Administration and IT Infrastructure Services**

Coursera partnered with Google

Jun 2018

https://coursera.org/share/7c0189a5c418d68f55cd16f77e1f5a9f

## **Web Developer Bootcamp**

Udemy Aug 2017

http://ude.my/UC-@C8V4ERF

## **Eastern Michigan University**

Bachelor's Degree, Fine Arts (Summa Cum Laude)

Aug 2009 - Dec 2013

Ypsilanti, MI

# References —

Jeremy Walker, VP Engineering, Groundspeed Analytics, Inc.

walker.r.jeremy@gmail.com | 248-730-1000

Ingus Mat Burleson, Sr. Full Stack Engineer & Team Lead, Groundspeed Analytics, Inc.

ingusmat@gmail.com | 810-728-2973

Matt Aho, Sr. Dev Ops Engineer, Groundspeed Analytics, Inc.

ahomatthew@gmail.com | 734-682-2763